In the face of an enemy, in the heart of one man, lies the soul of a warrior.
The Last Samurai is a drama, action, war film directed by Edward Zwick.
Nathan Algren is an American hired to instruct the Japanese army in the ways of modern warfare, which
finds him learning to respect the samurai and the honorable principles that rule them.
Pressed to destroy the samurai's way of life in the name of modernization and open trade, Algren
decides to become an ultimate warrior himself and to fight for their right to exist.
Nathan Algren, played by Tom Cruise.
Moritsugu Katsumoto, played by Ken Watanabe.
Simon Graham, played by Timothy Spall.
Col. Benjamin Bagley, played by Tony Goldwyn.
Ujio, played by Hiroyuki Sanada.
Taka, played by Koyuki.
The Last Samurai is a 2003 American epic period action drama film directed and produced by Edward Zwick, who also
co-wrote the screenplay with John Logan and Marshall Herskovitz from a story devised by Logan.
The film stars Tom Cruise, who also produced, along with Timothy Spall, Ken Watanabe, Billy
Connolly, Tony Goldwyn, Hiroyuki Sanada, and Koyuki Kato in supporting roles.
The film's plot was inspired by the 1877 Satsuma Rebellion, led by Saigō
Takamori, and the Westernization of Japan by foreign powers.
Cruise portrays Nathan Algren, an American captain of the 7th Cavalry Regiment, whose personal and emotional conflicts
bring him into contact with samurai warriors in the wake of the Meiji Restoration in 19th century Japan.
The character of Algren is very loosely based on Eugène Collache and Jules Brunet, both French
Imperial Guard officers who fought alongside Enomoto Takeaki in the earlier Boshin War.
The Last Samurai grossed a total of $456 million at the box office
and became the sixth-highest-grossing film of 2003.
It received mixed-to-positive reviews, with praise for the acting, visuals,
cinematography and Hans Zimmer's score, but criticism for some of its portrayals.
It was nominated for several awards, including four Academy Awards, three
Golden Globe Awards, and two National Board of Review Awards.
The film explores themes of japan, samurai, swordplay, general, sense of guilt.
The tone is emotional and intense.